Lev Perla

🤇 Kazakhstan, Astana Birth date: 11.08.1998

☑ levperla@mail.ru 🌭 +7 705 340 93 38 in linkedin.com/in/LevPerla github.com/LevPerla

Summary

Experienced Data Analyst with 3 years of experience who loves to automate processes and find data insights. Confident knowledge of analytical stack (Python, SQL, Power Bl). I combine professional and academic experience that has given me strong research, development, and product presentation skills.

Looking for opportunities in role of Product Analyst / Data Analyst / Data Scientist.

Professional Experience

Apr 2021 - Oct 2022 Gazprom Neft

Data Analyst | Chief Planning Specialist

- Conceptualized and developed a system for assessing the impact of competitors promotions on discount level using Python. Approximately 1 billion transactions were processed. Created weekly and monthly automatic analytical BI-reports for top management meetings.
- Developed a system for optimizing the price of a stelle at gasoline stations, considering the company's current strategy, micro and macro factors using Python.
- Conducted research on the price elasticity of demand for petroleum products using regression methods.
- Facilitated business communication with the data science department.
- Administered the department's Jira/Confluence space.

Jan 2021 - Apr 2021 Gazprom Neft

Data Scientist | Chief Specialist

Developed the forecasting module as part of the project to forecast wholesale petroleum product prices. Prepared the project for deployment in production using Docker.

Gazprom Neft Jan 2020 - Jan 2021

Intern Data Scientist

Developed time series forecasting algorithm using recurrent neural networks on Python and implemented it into existing forecasting system on R language. Managed to increase the quality of the forecasting system by 3% and reduced training time by half.

LTD «TriA», Moscow (Business application development)

Jul 2019 - Aug 2019

Developed an optimization algorithm for slicing sandwich panels with minimal residues using Python.

Education

Saint Petersburg State University	2020
Master, Business Information Analysis	2022
Master's dissertation: "Application of recurrent neural networks for financial time series forecasting"	
Saint Petersburg State University of Economics	2016
Bachelor, Economics, Specialization: Mathematical methods in Economics	2020
Graduate thesis: "Development of forecasting price models for wholesale petroleum supplies"	
Courses	

•	Game Analytics: from basics to advanced strategies (DevToDev)	2022
•	Computer vision course (Deep Learning School, MIPT)	2021
•	The basics of clean code and agile development in Data Science (Luxoft)	2020
•	Introduction to Data Science and Machine Learning (Bioinformatics Institute)	2019
•	Python: Basics and application (Bioinformatics Institute)	2019
•	Two-week B1 English course (EF International Language Center, Oxford)	2015

Achievements

- Winner of GPN Intelligence Cup 2019 in Advanced Analytics (Data science)
- Finalist of the GPN Intelligence Cup 2018 in the direction of "Business and Strategy" (3% of the best solutions)

Core competencies and technologies

- Program Languages: Python (pandas, numpy, sklearn, keras, pytorch, XGBoost), R
- Frameworks/Tools: Power BI, Git, Docker, Jira, Confluence
- Databases: MS SQL server, PostgreSQL
- Tasks: Machine learning algorithms, Time series forecasting, Computer vision, A/B tests analysis
- Languages: English (Upper-intermediate), Russian (Native)